All of these things have to be understood with great care and caution,
这一切必须万般谨慎正确理解
according to Śrīla Guru Mahārāj.
Srila Guru Maharaj这么说过
And I say this as someone who’s proceeded incautiously thousands of times.
我现在重提，因为有人不断重蹈覆辙疏忽这些
[Ekadashi | Why Fast?]
爱卡达西|为何要戒食？
But it will always be the key, the clue is devotion.
关键词总是奉爱
Just as we sing
就像歌里唱的
the śuddha-bhakata-caraṇa-reṇu bhajana-anukūla.
śuddha-bhakata-caraṇa-reṇu bhajana-anukūla.
What’s favourable for devotion, for devotion—
什么对奉爱有利
Not that what we think will be good, or …
不是我们自以为怎样是好的
That’s why this song is sung on Ekādaśī.
所以爱卡达西日才唱这首歌
мādhava-tithi, bhakti-jananī
мādhava-tithi, bhakti-jananī
Mādhava-tithi means the different times or days
Mādhava-tithi 指奎师那珍爱的不同日子
(to Mādhava— Mādhava means Kṛṣṇa).
对Madhava来说，Madhava指奎师那
Mādhava-tithi, bhakti-jananī—
Mādhava-tithi, bhakti-jananī—
by honouring these days, such as Ekādaśī, Dvādaśī and other:
通过荣耀这些日子，像爱卡达西、杜瓦达西
Janmāṣṭamī, Gaura Pūrṇimā— all these days …
Janmastami(奎师那显现日)、Gaura Purnima（玛哈帕布显现日）等等
He’s saying it will be favourable to the culture of devotion.
这将有利于培养奉爱
Not that it will free you from sinful activity …
并不是说这将清洗你的罪过
You did something wrong, now you’re really in trouble, call mom …
先做了错事惹了麻烦，再哭爹喊娘
You’re in a jam.
陷入困境里了
We need some karma-miśra-bhakti to get us out of a jam.
需要些夹杂功利心的奉爱行为（karma-miśra-bhakti）来摆脱困境
I’ve screwed up.
我搞砸了
Like those who’re saying things like this,
有些人说，
“Oh, I have blew it—on Ekādaśī, I’ll fast on this day and recover from that.”
“哎，我搞砸了。等到爱卡达西这天戒食，就能免除罪恶”
What happens by imitating Mahābhāgavatas?
模仿一等奉爱者（Mahābhāgavata）有什么后果？
Like just Bhíma was given this benediction, [from] who—from guru …
就像Bhima，他是从古茹那获得赐福
He didn’t go like, “Oh, well, let me think …”
他并不是，“这个,让我先想想...”
He asked his guru and he was told, “Yes”.
他询问了古茹，
He said, “I have this problem, I can’t observe them …”
他说，“我有这种困难，无法遵守这个日子..."
“Alright, on this day if you’ll do this, and for you, Bhíma,
"没事，在这天如果你这么做Bhima
it will be alright.”
你会没事的。”
Not like this—“I am doing that, me and Bhíma.”
并不是说，“我也这么做，我跟Bhima一样”
We are told, Śrīla Prabhupād cautions in the Upadeśāmṛta purport,
圣帕布帕德在《Upadeśāmṛta》的注释里警告我们
“You imitate Mahābhāgavata— you go down.”
“如果模仿一等奉爱者（Mahābhāgavata），你将云头上跌跤一落千丈。”
So, what it takes … following this idea, where did some go?
所以抱有这种想法的人
They don’t follow or observe any Ekādaśī during a year.
他们一年中没有遵守一次爱卡达西日
Just once a year, this day, they don’t take any water.
只是一年里有一天滴水不沾
Is that bhajana-anukūla? That’s favorable for devotion.
这是对奉爱有利的（bhajana-anukūla）吗？
It is to not understand this ...
而是没明白这些日子的意义
Dvādaśī is also bhajana-anukūla.
杜瓦达西（破戒日）也对奉爱有利
What do you have to do to observe Dvādaśī?
怎样遵守杜瓦达西日？
Break the fast. It’s very simple.
打破戒食，就这么简单
In one place Guru Mahārāj said, “More dear.”
Guru Maharaj说这更可贵
That can also be said … And how do you observe that?
这一天该怎样庆祝？
By taking a little grain—what was forbidden the day before—
吃一些谷类，前一天禁食的谷类
you take one grain as pleasing to Kṛṣṇa.
今天吃，会令奎师那开心
So what is the criterion— is what is pleasing to Kṛṣṇa.
因此，一切的前提是让奎师那开心
Not, “I am trying to escape the wrong I’ve done.”
而不是“我想清洗罪恶”
Like a bunch of karmis.
跟那些果报工作者似的
Go to confession and confess, “Bless me father for I have sinned.”
去忏悔“我犯下罪过，请神父保佑”
Confess on Saturday,
周六悔过
go to church on Sunday, and start sinning on Monday.
周日去教堂，然后周一再开始犯罪
It’s good work, if you can get it.
多好啊
Like mayi bhaktir hi … [Cc: 2.13.160] what the Vraja-gopīs said?
mayi bhaktir hi … (Cc: 2.13.160)，Vraja-gopis牧牛姑娘们说什么？
āhuś ca te nalina-nābha padāravindaṁ yogeśvarair hṛdi vicintyam agādha-bodhaiḥ
āhuś ca te nalina-nābha padāravindaṁ yogeśvarair hṛdi vicintyam agādha-bodhaiḥ
saṁsāra-kūpa-patitottaraṇāvalambaṁ gehaṁ juṣām api manasy udiyāt sadā naḥ [SB: 10.82.48]
saṁsāra-kūpa-patitottaraṇāvalambaṁ gehaṁ juṣām api manasy udiyāt sadā naḥ (SB: 10.82.48)
They told Kṛṣṇa, “We are not karmis, we are not yogis, we are not jñānis,
她们告诉奎师那，“我们不是果报工作者，不是瑜伽士，不是思辩者
we are fallen householders— saṁsāra-kūpa.
我们是堕落的家庭妇人-samsara-kupa
Like the andha-kūpa—you hear about it in the Scriptures—
经典里说的andha-kupa
the blind well of household life. That’s us.
家庭生活的盲目陷阱，指的就是我们
But even though that maybe who we are,
但尽管如此
still we can’t live without Your lotus feet.
我们还是无法离开您的莲花足。”
So in such a self-denigrating, sweet and affectionate way they present themselves.
她们就这样贬低自己，如此甜美有情
And they are worshipped as the highest devotees.
而她们被崇拜为最高等的奉爱者
So Śrīla Guru Mahārāj said quoting Saraswatī Ṭhākur—
Srila Guru Maharaj引用Saraswati Thakur的话
interestingly, he compared Ekādaśī, Mahādvādaśī, other days to.
他将爱卡达西日、玛哈杜瓦达西日等做了比喻
He said, “First understand, it is aprākṛta.”
他说，“首先要明白，这一切都是aprakrta
This is a very beautiful thing.
很美妙
Like we were saying before, it looks like it’s mundane, but it’s not.”
看似世俗，但一丝全无
So, how is it appeared to be? He said, “From a mundane point of view,
表面看是怎样？他说，“从世俗角度看
astrologically speaking, the Earth is under the influence of the Moon.
星象角度看，这时地球受月球的影响
Tides, also the flow of liquid;
潮汐活动，液体流动
at a particular time of the month the desire due to increased flow of rasā,
在一个月的特定日子里，由于rasa情悦的流动增强
the desire to enjoy is greater.
去享乐的欲望也更强烈
So you need to make yourself dry.
因此，你要干燥自己
So fasting is recommended and also abstaining from foods
所以推荐戒食，
This is from an external point of view.
这是外在的原因
And he pointed out also that each one comes,
他还说，每次
the two times of month—the most intense, full moon, and amāvāsyā, new moon—
一月两次，最强烈的是满月那次，接着是amavasya新月那次
so few days before that you make an adjustment.
在这些日子来临前，你开始调整
Pull back.
后退
But still this is external.
但这依旧是外在原因
But there aprākṛta, here is where aprākṛta comes in.
但那个世界是aprākṛta（看似世俗，但毫不世俗）
Kṛṣṇa—His desire at this time is also greater.
奎师那，他这时的欲望也更强烈
But what is His desire?
他的欲望是什么？
When we say Kṛṣṇa’s desire, or the kāma of the Vraja-gopīs,
当我们说到奎师那的欲望，或者vraja-gopi牧牛姑娘的欲望
this isn’t mundane desire.
这并不是世俗的欲望
What’s pleasing to Kṛṣṇa is devotion.
奎师那喜爱的是奉献
It’s inconceviable how the Vraja-gopīs serve, but nontheless it’s devotion.
Vraja-gopīs牧牛姑娘们的服务是不可思议的，那都是奉献
ātmendriya-prīti-vāñchā—tāre bali ‘kāma’ kṛṣṇendriya-prīti-icchā dhare ‘prema’ nāma [Cc: 1.4.165]
ātmendriya-prīti-vāñchā—tāre bali ‘kāma’ kṛṣṇendriya-prīti-icchā dhare ‘prema’ nāma (Cc: 1.4.165)
What’s done to satisfy our own notion of things and senses—
为满足我们自己的感官的
that’s kāma.
是kama欲望
What’s done to satisfy Kṛṣṇa, kṛṣṇendriya, Kṛṣṇa-indriya,
而去满足奎师那的事情, krsna-indriya
the senses of Kṛṣṇa, in Kṛṣṇa consideration—
奎师那的感官，为奎师那着想
‘prema’ nāma, that’s prema.
那就是prema
But they may look similar.
虽然两者看起来相似
Guru Mahārāj said, “They may look similar, but they are different—
Guru Maharaj说，“两者看似相同，但天壤之别
North Pole, South Pole in difference.”
如南极和北极。”
So what is really behind this, why is it mādhava-tithi, bhakti-jananī,
所以这背后真正的意义，mādhava-tithi, bhakti-jananī,
giving birth to devotion?
为何这些会生成奉献？
Because at this time Kṛṣṇa’s desire is more;
因为这时奎师那的欲望更强烈
the higher devotees, Guru Mahārāj said,
Guru Maharaj说那些高等的奉爱者
they’re giving so much attention to Kṛṣṇa at that time,
那时全关注在奎师那上
they don’t have time to even think about eating, anything.
根本不会去考虑吃东西
They are not leaving His side for a moment.
他们对奎师那寸步不离
They are just serving Him.
就在旁边服务他
Can’t think about eating … and forget everything …
废寝忘食，心无旁骛
The higher devotees.
那些高等的奉爱者们
And from this plane also the devotees are thinking,
奉爱者们的想法还有
“Alright, so for these external reasons we are going to fast this way and that way
“嗯，出于这些外在的理由
to check the mundane tendency.
我们也会这样那样的戒食，来检测下我们的世俗面
But, more importantly, we’re going to serve.”
但更重要的是，我们要去服务。
By a little bit of services this time, it’s magnified.
这时一丁点的服务，都会被放大
It’s like, what do you call that— exponentially.
指数增长
Little service draws greater remuneration at that time.
那时的一小点服务都将带来最大的报酬
But the emphasis, like we told earlier, will be on service.
但像刚讲过的，重点在于服务
Not some trick; a trick I can do to achieve some devotional position.
不是来获得奉爱身份的什么手段
That would be mundane.
那就变成世俗的了
That would be objective evolution, not subjective evolution.
变成客体进化，而不是主观意识的进化
That would be again manipulating the mundane to achieve the spiritual.
又变成企图利用世俗物来达成灵性目的
That it’s not that by fasting you get devotion.
不是说，通过戒食你将获得奉爱
But by, as Gurudev said, by giving your energy to Kṛṣṇa.
而是像Gurudev说的，将你的能量给奎师那
Once in Nabadwīp he said that, like, “If you don’t feel something …”
他在纳瓦兑普时说过，"如果你一点感觉都没有,"
(there are different levels we know of observing:
遵守戒食有不同的程度
no water, some water, some fruits,
不喝水、喝一点水、吃一些水果
this, that, fast up to this time and then after that …—
这样那样，戒食到几时
different ways.
等等不同的方式
But Gurudev, the bottomline, he said, “If you don’t feel something.”
Gurudev说，底限是
And we all, I think, we know what that means.
大家都知道那天的感受
Mahananda Prabhu once said, “Why is it like you could skip breakfast
Mahananda Prabhu说过，
It’s true.
是这样的
Or you can tolerate your hair, your fingernails, everything.
或者平时你的头发指甲一切都没啥问题
On Ekādaśī your fingernails will drive you crazy, and you want to cut them.
但爱卡达西这天，指甲能让你抓狂，你就是想剪
Or get a haircut, shave your hair.
或者理发，剃头
And we know this is true, by our practical experience.
我们有这种体验，确实如此
So Gurudev said, “If you don’t feel something on this fast …”
所以Gurudev说，
You’ve got to feel something!
你肯定有感觉的！
And Gurudev said, “In that way something’s being offered to Kṛṣṇa.”
Gurudev说，”那样的话，你就供奉给了奎师那一些东西“
That’s what he said: some of your energy,
你的一些能量，你已经感受到了的
that’s what’s being given to Kṛṣṇa.
能量已经给予了奎师那
So we are happy about that.
我们也很开心